export const week1 = [
  {
    question: "1. Who was the first European to build a factory in India.?",
    options: [
      "Vasco De Gama",
      "Pedro Alvarez Cabrel",
      "Fancis de Almeida",
"Afonso de Albuqurque"],
    answer: "Pedro Alvarez Cabrel",
  },


  {
    question: "2. Who will the real founder of Portuguese power in East?",
    options: ["Almeida", "Albuquerque", "Henry the Navigator", "Nuno Da Cunha"],
    answer: "Albuquerque",
  },


  {
    question: "3. Which was not a cause of decline of Portuguese power in India??",
    options: ["Rise of regional power's", 
      "Dishonest trade practices", 
      "Fall of Vijaynagar empire", 
      "Discovery of North America"],
    answer: "Discovery of North America",
  },


  {
  question: `4. Chronology of Dutch factory established:<br><br>
  <table border="0" style="width:100%">
    <tr>
      <th align="left">List-I (Dutch Factory)</th>
      <th align="left">List-II (Year)</th>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td>(1) Masulipatnam</td>
      <td>(a) 1605</td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td>(2) Surat</td>
      <td>(b) 1616</td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td>(3) Karikal</td>
      <td>(c) 1645</td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td>(4) Cochin</td>
      <td>(d) 1663</td>
    </tr>
  </table><b>Code</b>`,
  options: [
    "A. 1-b 2-c 3-d 4-a",
    "B. 1-d 2-c 3-b 4-a",
    "C. 1-d 2-c 3-b 4-a",
    "D. 1-a 2-c 3-b 4-d"
  ],
  answer: "D. 1-a 2-c 3-b 4-d"
},


  {
question:
"5. Battle of Hooghly (1759) led to the defeat of \n which European power?",
options: ["A. Portuguese", "B. French", "C. Dutch", "D. Danes"],
answer: "C. Dutch"
},

{
question:
"6. First Golden Farman was issued to English East India Company by -",
options: [
"A. Farukhsiyar",
"B. Shah Shuja",
"C. Abdullah Qutab Shah of Golconda",
"D. Aurangzeb"
],
answer: "C. Abdullah Qutab Shah of Golconda"
}, 


{
  question: "7. Who was considered as the father of subsidiary alliance in India?",
  options: [
    "A. Warren Hasting",
    "B. Lord Wellesley",
    "C. Francis Dupleix",
    "D. Lord Cornwallis"
  ],
  answer: "C. Francis Dupleix"
},

{
  question: "8. Who established the French factory in Surat in 1667?",
  options: [
    "A. Colbert",
    "B. Godehen",
    "C. Caron",
    "D. Mercara"
  ],
  answer: "C. Caron"
},


{
  question: `9. Match the following Books and writers:<br><br>
  <table border="0" style="width:100%">
    <tr>
      <th align="left">List-I</th>
      <th align="left">List-II</th>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td>(1) India conquered</td>
      <td>(a) William Irvine</td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td>(2) Army of the Indian Mughals</td>
      <td>(b) Jon Wilson</td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td>(3) The Agrarian System of Mughal India</td>
      <td>(c) Sidneyowen</td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td>(4) The fall of the Mughal empire</td>
      <td>(d) Irfan Habib</td>
    </tr>
  </table><br><b>Code</b>`,
  options: [
    "A. 1-c, 2-a, 3-b, 4-d",
    "B. 1-b, 2-c, 3-d, 4-a",
    "C. 1-b, 2-a, 3-c, 4-d",
    "D. 1-d, 2-c, 3-b, 4-a"
  ],
  answer: "B. 1-b, 2-c, 3-d, 4-a"
},


{
  question: "10. What was MAKTABS?",
  options: [
    "A. Coingage of Deccan Kingdoms",
    "B. Administrative unit during medieval era",
    "C. Educational Institution",
    "D. Judicial System"
  ],
  answer: "C. Educational Institution"
},


{
  question: `I2. Match the Art & Culture and Artist:<br><br>
  <table border="0" style="width:100%">
    <tr>
      <th align="left">List-I (Art & Culture)</th>
      <th align="left">List-II (Artist)</th>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td>(1) Bada Imambara</td>
      <td>(a) Asaf-Ud-Daula</td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td>(2) Astronomical Observatory</td>
      <td>(b) Sawai Jai Singh</td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td>(3) Heer-Ranjha</td>
      <td>(c) Waris Shah</td>
    </tr>
    <tr>
      <td>(4) Shah jo Risalo</td>
      <td>(d) Shah Abdul Latif</td>
    </tr>
  </table><br><b>Code</b>`,
  options: [
    "A. 1-a, 2-b, 3-c, 4-d",
    "B. 1-b, 2-c, 3-d, 4-a",
    "C. 1-c, 2-d, 3-a, 4-b",
    "D. 1-d, 2-a, 3-b, 4-c"
  ],
  answer: "A. 1-a, 2-b, 3-c, 4-d"
},

{
  question: `13. Arrange the Governor Generals in ascending order of their appointment:<br><br>
  <ol>
    <li>Sir John Shore</li>
    <li>Lord Hardinge I</li>
    <li>Lord Hastings</li>
    <li>Lord Amherst</li>
  </ol>`,
  options: [
    "A. 1234",
    "B. 2341",
    "C. 1243",
    "D. 1342"
  ],
  answer: "D. 1342"
}







   












];
